WILMAR GERMAN FAJARDO MENDIETA

Astrophysicist & Data Specialist

During my career, I have learned that knowledge is built continuously based on questions or needs, leading to unsolved problems. No matter how difficult it may seem, every problem can be solved, by breaking it down into small easy-to-understand parts. "Love is energy of life." R. Browning.



CONTACT

- 🐈 February 7, 1992. Colombian 💳
- Bogotá, Colombia. Zip 111611
- **(+57)** 3194490967
- wilmargfm1021@gmail.com
- in Wilmar Fajardo
- @wgfajardom
- Orcid

SKILLS

Hard skills

Advanced

Python, Pyspark, Databricks, LaTeX, IDL, Machine Learning, Exploratory Data Analysis, Statistics

Intermediate

Azure, Git, SQL, Artificial Intelligence, Unix, Hadoop, DevOps, Scrum

Basic

Docker, Flask, HTML, CSS, Tableau

Soft skills

- Analytical thinking
- Assertive communication
- 👺 Collaborative work
- Continuous learning
- Commitment

Languages

Spanish English Italian



CERTIFICATES

[DP-100] Azure Data Scientist **Databricks Developer Foundations** [AZ-900] Azure Fundamentals [DS4A] Data Science For All

INTERESTS

Energy industry 4th Industrial Revolution		
Sustainable Develo	opment Nat	tural Sciences
Applied math	Heliophysics	Geography
Sports Literature Family & Friends		

PROFILE

Background in academic research on physics and astronomy. Having almost five years of experience in technology industry, being involved on several data-related projects. Passionate about clean & affordable energies, sustainability, and grid automation. This is the reason why I am willing to work on the energy industry.

WORK HISTORY

Mar 2022 - Current

i IBM Chile - Experis

Data Specialist

♀ Remote from Colombia

Technical support for on-premise (Hadoop ecosystem) and on-cloud (GCP) infrastructures of Banco de Chile. Migration of projects between both infrastructures, bug-fixing, and collaborative work with different business teams.

Mar 2022

1DATA SAS

Datamining Analyst

9 Bogotá, Colombia

Implementation of ML and AI solutions for a diverse set of customers, coming for a wide variety of industries. All projects were developed on Azure. Around ten workshops about the cloud computing capabilities on Azure were taught.

Jan 2018 - Sep 2019

m MOCA Platform

Data Scientist

🗣 Barcelona, Spain - Bogotá, Colombia

Business Intelligence (BI) role. Channel between developers and commercials. Research about urban human mobility. Looking for funding opportunities via international callouts related to Smart Cities.

Feb 2017 - May 2017

universidad Nacional de Colombia Teaching Assistant

P Bogotá, Colombia

Teaching the course ASTROPHYSICAL OBJECTS which was directed to university students non-involved with sciences or related topics. The main objects present int the universe were described according to the physics.

The Work Portfolio gives a detailed view of my work experience.

EDUCATION

Aug 2015 - Sep 2018

M.Sc. Astronomy Universidad Nacional de Colombia

P Bogotá, Colombia

Jun 2014 - Sep 2014

Research Experience Purdue University

♥ Indiana, USA

Feb 2009 - Mar 2015

B.Sc. Physics Universidad Nacional de Colombia

P Bogotá, Colombia

The Academic Portfolio describes in depth my formal education.